The key increases your luck just by wearing it.
光是擁有這把鑰匙就能有好運氣
It stirs a person's desire and sends them mad.
它能勾起人的欲望，讓人為之瘋狂
The devil's key.
這就是惡魔鑰匙
Since long ago, many people have died
很久以前 為了將99把惡魔鑰匙全部奪到手
in their scramble for all 99 keys.
很多人命喪黃泉
Where's the key?
鑰匙在哪裡？
Thirteen years ago, my father was killed by a man who came after his key.
13年前 我父親被一個覬覦鑰匙的人殺害
Dad! Dad!
爸爸
I returned to Japan to investigate a series of mysterious deaths,
我返回日本調查一系列神祕死亡事件
-and was reconnected with old friends. -Teruasa!
-同時和老朋友恢復聯繫 -照朝君
I had myself fooled
我還以為
that you were here to take back your father's company.
你回來是為了奪回你父親的公司
The key summoned the devil, and a cruel game of death.
鑰匙召喚出了惡魔 並啟動了一場殘酷的生死遊戲
ACMA:GAME
ACMA:GAME遊戲
The game begins!
遊戲開始
If I lose,
如果我輸了
you can kill me on the spot.
你可以當場殺了我
I'll risk my life with all I've got.
我會冒著生命危險全力以赴
It's live or die!
不是生就是死
Teruasa Oda, victory is yours.
織田照朝，你贏了
Just like Maruko,
像丸子一樣
there will be others chosen by the key
這裡會有其他人被鑰匙選中
who will cross your path.
然後跟你對上
I will find you, and make you pay for killing my father.
我會找到你的 讓你為殺害我父親付出代價
The debts of ACMA:GAME
ACMA:GAME遊戲的債
must always be paid.
總是要還的
A debt to be paid…
欠的債總是要還的…
Mitsuhide's gone.
光秀不見了
I pulled off a narrow win.
我在遊戲中險勝
But as a bitter price for victory,
但勝利的獎賞令人痛心
I may have taken someone's life.
我可能奪取了他人的性命
But why?
但怎麼會這樣？
Teruasa,
照朝君
what do you intend to do with the key?
你打算怎麼處置這把鑰匙？
Seiji's killer warned you.
殺害清司的人警告過你
There will be others chosen by the key
這裡會有其他人被鑰匙選中
who will cross your path.
然後跟你對上
I'll be waiting for them.
那我就恭候他們
If I can win the games
如果我能贏得遊戲
and collect the keys
並集齊鑰匙
-it will lead me to him. -Teruasa.
-我就能找到那個人 -照朝君
A pen is a useful tool for writing.
筆是非常有用的書寫工具
However,
但是
it can also pierce a person's heart.
它也能刺穿人的心臟
Both desires and the means to fulfill them
欲望和實現欲望的手段
are there for the taking.
在於你如何利用
That's exactly why…
正因為如此
you must choose to listen
你要選擇
to what's in here.
不違背本心
I will.
我知道了
I'm telling you, it was a real devil.
我沒騙你，那是真的惡魔
Will you calm down?
冷靜，悠季
It was fuzzy, with horns sticking out its head, and－
它毛茸茸的頭上還長了角，而且…
And it was huge, as big as this.
它非常高大，有這麼大
You were just dreaming.
妳一定是做了夢
But the leader of the Maruko Family vanished.
但丸子家族的少爺就消失了
Yeah, well, I didn't really get a good look at him.
那個姓丸子的傢伙， 我沒有清楚看到他
But you saw this room disappear.
但你看到這個房間消失了
Well, yeah.
是這樣沒錯
Was that a dream too?
難道那也是做夢嗎？
Teruasa,
照朝君
did the devil make Maruko disappear?
是惡魔讓丸子消失的嗎？
Yeah, Teruasa, what actually happened?
是啊，照朝，到底發生了什麼事？
You two must not say anything to anyone about what you saw here.
你們在這裡看到的事 絕對不能跟任何人說
And from now on
還有從今以後
you've got to keep out of this.
你們不要介入這件事
-Why?
-為什麼？
It's dangerous.
因為這很危險
You mean the devil's key?
你是說這把惡魔鑰匙嗎？
Devil's key?
惡魔鑰匙？
It's the key to the game run by the devil.
這把鑰匙能啟動由惡魔管理的遊戲
If you win the game,
如果在遊戲中獲勝
you can take anything you want from the loser.
你就能獲得敗者的任何東西
What are you going to do next?
接下來你打算怎麼辦？
Find who killed my father.
找到殺害我父親的凶手
Alone?
就靠你自己？
Are you crazy?
那樣很危險
Leave it to the police.
把這件事交給警方處理吧
You can't just go hunting down a criminal by yourself.
追蹤犯人可不是外行人能辦到的事
I've gotten this far alone.
我一個人也走了這麼遠
Isn't that enough?
那樣還不夠嗎？
You're finally back home. Isn't it time to live your life?
你好不容易回國了 不是應該過自己的生活嗎？
As long as I have this key, I can't hope for a normal life.
我只要手握這把鑰匙 就不能奢望過正常人的生活
Is that right?
是嗎？
Then why don't you use the key
那你為什麼不利用這把鑰匙
to win back your father's company from Miyanouchi Group?
把你爸爸的公司 從宮之內集團那裡贏回來？
Can't you take whatever you want?
你不是能奪取任何想要的東西嗎？
The Ui I knew…
我所認識的初…
would have told me to win it back honestly.
會讓我堂堂正正地把它贏回來
Get your head out of the clouds.
別幻想了
Ui.
初君
Thanks for sharing the data for losing one's temper.
感謝分享生氣的數據
Anyway,
總之
just stay out of it.
你們不要介入這件事
Got it.
知道了
Have it your way.
隨便你
Wait. Where are you going? Ouch!
等等，你要去哪裡？好痛
Gosh. Are you okay?
妳沒事吧？
That stings.
好痛
Shirota's closing in!
城田在逼近
Hyodo can't do anything!
兵頭毫無反抗之力
He's slipped! It's a narrow escape!
他掙開了鉗制，真是千鈞一髮
A knee strike from Hyodo!
兵頭發動了膝擊
Now Hyodo's lucky punch!
現在兵頭給出了幸運一擊
Pounding him into the ground!
把對手擊倒在地
Pound him! We have a winner!
繼續擊打，冠軍誕生了
Tonight, the goddess of victory
今晚，兵頭猛
is smiling on Takeru Hyodo!
受到勝利女神的眷顧
Takeru Hyodo is back in the game!
兵頭猛強勢回歸了
Congratulations, Chairman Miyanouchi.
恭喜，宮之內會長
You've gotten hold of a devil's key.
你獲得了一把惡魔鑰匙
Who are you?
你是誰？
You can think of me as a preacher to the devil's key.
你可以把我當成 惡魔鑰匙的傳道者
The keys hold many secrets.
這些鑰匙蘊藏著許多祕密
And there is a method to collecting them.
有一種方法可以收集這些鑰匙
My accomplice will explain all you need to know.
我的手下會跟你解釋 你需要知道的一切
Chairman!
會長
-Cheers!
-乾杯
A five game winning streak!
五戰連勝
Congratulations!
恭喜你
Another one?
再喝一杯吧？
You've been doing well lately…
你最近真是狀態很好
haven't you, Hyodo?
對吧，兵頭君？
Are you a fan? Want an autograph?
你是粉絲？想要我的親筆簽名？
I guess you've realized this key is making you lucky?
我猜你已經發現 這把鑰匙能讓你走運了吧？
Leave us.
通通出去
Who are you?
你是什麼人？
With more keys,
如果能擁有更多鑰匙
you could get even richer
你就能變得更富有
and even more powerful.
同時你也能變得更加強大
Oh, didn't you know?
你不知道嗎？
More keys?
更多鑰匙？
There are others?
還有別的鑰匙嗎？
Of course.
當然有啊
I know someone with three.
有個人手握著三把鑰匙
OROCHI, is this it?
大蛇，是這個嗎？
There's a Hellenistic mural from the 4th century BC,
有一幅公元前四世紀的希臘化時代壁畫
that depicts a demon and a key.
描繪了一個惡魔和一把鑰匙
You sure this is a good idea? Teruasa told you not to get involved.
妳確定這樣做沒問題嗎？ 照朝君叫你們不要介入
It's only a bit of research.
我只是做一點調查而已
When was that photo taken?
這是什麼時候拍的照片？
Second year of junior high.
初二的時候
SCHOOL FESTIVAL
（校慶）
We took it at the school festival.
這是我們在校慶時拍的照片
So that's called a "memory", right?
這就是所謂的“回憶”，對吧？
Yep. A good memory.
對，美好的回憶
Sorry I'm late, OROCHI.
久等了，大蛇
Yuriko! Hello.
阿姨好
I'm excited for my emotions class.
很期待能跟妳上情緒課
Yes, let's get to it.
好，那我們開始吧
Wait. I just remembered.
我想起來了
Are the keys numbered?
這些是鑰匙的編號嗎？
Or do the codes mean something?
還是傳遞某種訊息的代碼？
Hold on.
失陪一下
Yuki?
喂，悠季？
Teruasa?
照朝君？
Is now a good time?
現在方便說話嗎？
Sure.
方便
It's a bit last minute, but I thought we could go get that video today.
雖然很臨時 但我覺得我們今天可以去拿影片
Video?
影片？
Don't you remember? After the school festival in second year,
你不記得了嗎？初二的校慶結束後
the three of us made a video.
我們三個拍了一段影片
It was called, To Us When We Are 20.
叫“致20歲的我們”
The thing we buried at school?
我們埋在學校的那個東西？
Yeah. That's the one.
對，就是它了
We agreed to dig it up after we all turned 20.
我們說好要等我們都到20歲後 再把它挖出來的
Our school's going to be demolished, so it'll be lost forever.
學校就要被拆除了 到時候影片就再也找不到了
So why don't we go and dig it up?
我們今天去把它挖出來吧？
Sorry.
不好意思
I can't today.
今天不行
Right.
好吧
Because Teruasa went to study abroad,
因為照朝君去國外留學了
you couldn't dig it up like you agreed.
所以你們沒能按照說好的那樣 把它挖出來
You lost contact with Teruasa
妳跟照朝君斷了音訊
and have been searching for him ever since.
從此以後，妳就一直在尋找他的下落
OROCHI…
大蛇…
Then how about tomorrow?
那明天怎麼樣？
Or the day after?
還後天呢？
I'm sorry.
抱歉
I can't.
我去不了了
Oh, no.
糟糕
Is this called "rejection"?
這叫“拒絕”嗎？
Mom! Don't tell OROCHI everything single thing.
媽媽，不要什麼事都告訴大蛇
Teruasa just thinks it's dangerous for me to spend time with him.
照朝君只是覺得 我在他身邊會有危險
But
但是
if it's so dangerous…
如果真的這麼危險
all the more reason to help him.
我就更應該幫他了
This emotion must be "love".
這種情感一定就是“愛”吧
What? Tomorrow?
什麼？明天？
Let's dig it up and have a screening.
我們把它挖出來，然後播放吧
Is he gonna be there too?
那個人也會去嗎？
He has a name, you know?
不是“那個人”，人家叫照朝君
But actually, Teruasa said no.
不過照朝君拒絕了我
It might be a good chance for you two to make friends.
這也許是你們重歸於好的絕佳機會
-So… -Next!
-所以… -下一位
You're saying you want me to ask Teruasa?
妳是要我叫照朝一起去？
Yes, please.
麻煩你啦
Mr. Saito, U.U. Engineering.
UU工程公司的齊藤先生
Yes.
是
I'm gonna pass.
我恐怕沒辦法
What? Wait.
等等
-Thanks for waiting. -No problem.
-久等了 -沒關係
I'm looking for additional funding.
我想請求追加融資
-Additional funding? -Yes.
-追加融資？ -對
I give up.
我放棄了
Do you want a ride home?
要我送你回去嗎？
I'm okay.
不用了
I need to make a detour.
我需要繞路去別的地方
I'll see you later.
再見
MERGER WITH HIGASHI JUNIOR HIGH SCHOOL
（與東中學校合併）
It really will be lost forever.
它真的要永遠消失了
I－
我…
I was in the area.
我正好在附近
-Anyway. -Wait!
-先這樣 -等等
Wait a sec! No excuses!
等一下，不要找藉口
You came all this way, so let's get it.
你都大老遠跑來了 我們就去挖影片吧
It won't take long.
不會花很長時間的
Come on!
快走
Over here.
在這邊
We buried it somewhere here.
我們就埋在這裡的某個地方
Can you remember?
你還記得嗎？
Wasn't it next to that tire?
是不是在那個輪胎附近？
TIME CAPSULE JUNE 24TH, 2012
（時間膠囊）
Hey, Ui. Let's bury it here.
就埋在這裡吧
Isn't that obvious? Someone'll find it.
這太明顯了吧？別人會發現的
Move over.
你過去一點
From the tire,
從輪胎這裡開始
one, two, three steps.
走一、二、三步
How about here?
這裡怎麼樣？
From the tire…
從輪胎這裡開始…
One.
一
Two.
二
Three steps.
三步
Here?
這裡？
Do you remember what you said in the video?
還記得你在影片裡說了什麼嗎？
I just chatted nonsense.
我就說了一些傻話
Like whether I'd have a driver's license,
比如我20歲的時候
or if I'd get a girlfriend by the time I was 20.
是不是拿到了駕照 或者會不會有女朋友
-Did you? -What?
-你有過嗎？ -什麼？
Did you get one? A girlfriend?
你有過女朋友嗎？
Well,
這個嘛
I've dated a few girls.
我交過幾個女朋友
What about now?
那現在呢？
Not at the moment.
現在沒有
Can I have that?
給我吧
-It's here. This is it. -Yes.
找到了，在這裡
Yes. You found it.
對，你找到了
TIME CAPSULE JUNE 24TH, 2012
（時間膠囊）
We found it.
找到了
MEMORIES 2012.6.24
（回憶，2012年6月24日）
LOAN APPLICATION
（貸款申請書）
It'll take at least one month to get a loan.
至少需要一個月才能獲得貸款
You've got a message.
你收到了一則訊息
It's from Yuki.
來自悠季的訊息
Read it out.
唸出來吧
"Change of plan. We got the video.
“計畫有變，我們找到影片了
I'm waiting at school with Teruasa,
我和照朝君在學校等你
so you should join us after work.
你忙完工作後要來找我們
Yuki."
悠季，就這樣”
She's with Teruasa?
她和照朝在一起？
SCHOOL FESTIVAL
（校慶）
Hey, Ui!
初
I told you to bring 30,000 yen.
我說了要你帶三萬日元
I don't have that kind of money.
我沒有那麼多錢
-Let me check your wallet. -Give it back.
-讓我檢查你的錢包 -還給我
Ui!
初
Teruasa.
照朝
What are you doing?
你們在做什麼？
Did they take something?
他們拿走什麼東西了嗎？
It doesn't matter.
沒關係
-But wait－ -Forget it.
-可是… -算了
Leave me alone.
不用你管
Yuki,
悠季
do you know who put this here?
你知道是誰把這個放在這裡的嗎？
No. It was there when I got here.
不知道，我到的時候它就在那裡了
Okay, class is starting. Get to your seats, please.
好了，要上課了，大家都坐好
What happened to your face?
你的臉怎麼了？
Fell over in soccer.
踢足球的時候摔倒了
What? I just fell over.
幹嘛？我是真的摔倒了
is the company doing okay?
公司營運得還好嗎？
It sounded like the funding fell through.
聽說之前融資失敗了
I'm worried about it too,
我也在擔心這個
but Ui said to leave the business side to him.
但初君說經營的事交給他
He won't say much.
他不願意跟我說太多
I see.
原來如此
Maybe he didn't want to worry you.
也許他不想讓妳擔心
I suspect that is because Ui is such a lovely person.
我猜這是因為初君是一個很善良的人
That's exactly why we've gotta keep working hard, for his sake.
所以我們要為了他繼續努力工作
OROCHI,
大蛇
you should be more open with your friends.
對於親近的人 我們在說話時大可以直言不諱
That's more human.
這樣更人性化
Really? Got it.
這樣啊？知道啦
Yuki!
悠季
Teruasa Oda?
織田照朝
You have a devil's key. Hand it over.
你有一把惡魔鑰匙，交出來
Stop!
別動她
Who are you?
你是誰？
That key…
那把鑰匙…
Hurry up, hand it over!
快點，交出來
I heard you!
我知道了
Just calm down.
你先冷靜
The key
鑰匙
is right here.
就在這裡
Amazing.
太好了
You can have anything.
它能讓你擁有一切
Money, women, power. Whatever you want.
金錢、女人、權力 想要什麼就有什麼
I was too careless. What now?
我太大意了，現在該怎麼辦？
Give it here or I'll kill her!
快交過來，否則我就殺了她
Okay!
我知道了
I'll put the key down there.
我這就把鑰匙扔過去
Yuki, run!
悠季，快跑
Ui! Ui!
初！
Teruasa, escape with Yuki!
照朝，趕快帶悠季離開這裡
I can't let anyone else die.
我不能再讓任何人死去
You must listen to what's in here.
你要選擇不違背本心
Come out, devil.
出來吧，惡魔
What's happening?
這是怎麼回事？
My name is Gado.
我叫卡多
I'm the ACMA:GAME master.
我是ACMA:GAME遊戲管理者
I promise to judge fairly.
我保證會做出公正的評判
It was my only option to save you both.
我只有這樣才能救你們
The space chosen by Teruasa Oda,
織田照朝選擇的空間
the entire school grounds, has been totally shut off.
也就是整個校園，已被完全隔絕
It is impossible to leave or enter the premises
想要進出這個區域是不可能的
until the game is over.
直至遊戲結束
Communication with the outside world has been cut off.
與外界的通訊已被切斷
Yuck!
好難吃
Blunt weapons taste like mud.
不鋒利的武器嚐起來像泥土一樣
Gado, first I want to ask you about the last game.
卡多，首先我想問一個 關於上一場遊戲的問題
What?
什麼問題？
Why did Maruko disappear because of the debt to be paid?
丸子之所以會消失 是因為要清償遊戲的賭債嗎？
Exactly.
沒錯
He was obliterated, in accordance with the rules.
按照遊戲規則，他被除掉了
Rules?
規則？
So the devil made him disappear.
果然是惡魔除掉了他
You!
妳
So we meet again?
我們又見面了？
Are you going to faint?
這次妳還要暈倒嗎？
Who are the players? You and Takeru Hyodo?
遊戲玩家是誰？你和兵頭猛嗎？
Yes.
對
How do you know my name?
你怎麼會知道我的名字？
What the hell is this monster?
這怪物是什麼鬼東西？
Then Teruasa Oda, tell me what you demand.
那麼織田照朝，提出你的要求吧
I want Takeru Hyodo to tell me everything he knows about the keys.
我要兵頭猛 把所有關於鑰匙的資訊告訴我
Accepted.
同意
Takeru Hyodo,
兵頭猛
what do you wish for from Teruasa Oda?
你想從織田照朝那裡得到什麼？
Wish for?
得到什麼？
Let me explain.
我來解釋一下
In this game,
在這個遊戲中
the winner will take all of the keys
贏家可以奪走
in the loser's possession.
輸家手上所有的鑰匙
That's not all.
不僅如此
You may meet the opponent's bet with a wager of the same value.
你可以用價值相等的賭注與對手賭
You can take anything, such as fortune,
你可以奪走任何事物，比如財富
or even,
甚至是
his life.
他的性命
Are you serious?
你說真的？
I guess once the game is over,
我猜遊戲結束後
these three will report you for threatening them with a knife.
這三個人會報警，稱你用刀威脅他們
If you want to avoid that, you could wager their lives.
你如果不想進警察局 可以拿他們的性命做賭注
Okay, if I win, I want all three dead!
好，如果我贏了 我要他們三個全部去死
Demand accepted.
我同意這個要求
What is going on?
這是什麼意思？
This is the real thing.
這是來真的
If I lose, you can take my life!
如果我輸了，你可以要了我的命
How entertaining. It is done－
真有意思，我同意…
Don't you dare!
開什麼玩笑？
His life is mine to take.
該要他性命的人是我
Gado,
卡多
I want the right to take Hyodo's life freely.
我要自由奪取兵頭猛性命的權利
A game of death. My favorite.
生死遊戲，我的最愛
Accepted.
同意
Now take your oaths.
現在宣誓吧
The ritual to set ACMA:GAME in motion.
這是啟動ACMA:GAME遊戲的儀式
I will fight for my desires.
我會為我的欲望而戰
I will triumph for my desires.
我會為我的欲望奪勝
Swear on the devil.
向惡魔宣誓吧
I will fight for my desires.
我會為我的欲望而戰
I will triumph for my desires.
我會為我的欲望奪勝
-I swear on the devil.
-我向惡魔宣誓
Oaths accepted.
我接受你們的宣誓
Let the game begin!
遊戲開始
"Shadow Step."
“映影頭踏”
In this game, you must step on your opponent's shadow.
在這個遊戲裡 你們必須踩中對手的影子
The sun?
太陽？
We've gone back in time?
時光倒流了？
Each game takes place in a designated area.
每一輪遊戲均在指定的區域進行
If you step on your opponent's shadow from the neck upwards,
如果你們踩中對手脖子以上的影子
you score one point.
就能得一分
The first to get two points is the winner.
先得兩分者獲勝
I played the same game as a kid.
我小時候玩過這個遊戲
I've stopped time.
我將時間靜止了
First, the one who used the devil's key to start the game,
在遊戲開始之前 使用惡魔鑰匙開啟遊戲的人
is given a devil's power which he may unleash.
可以獲得在遊戲中解鎖的惡魔之力
There are many different powers. Look at your hand.
惡魔之力有很多種，看看你的手
The devil's power that you can release
你可以解鎖的惡魔之力
is called "Limited Perfect,"
叫“有限完美”
also known as "One Minute Freeze."
也叫“凍結一分鐘”
Limited Perfect.
有限完美
Any object that you touch
你碰到的任何物體
will be frozen still for one minute.
都將凍結一分鐘
But it may only be used once during the game.
但在遊戲中只能用一次
I will give you both a word of warning.
我要警告兩位
In the unlikely event that one of the players dies during the game,
在遊戲中，如果有一方不慎死亡
the game cannot be terminated
遊戲將無法結束
and this space will remain closed for all eternity.
這個空間也將永遠無法解除封鎖
Be very careful.
這一點要特別注意
Understood.
明白了
Hyodo, do you understand?
兵頭，你明白了嗎？
This whole thing's nonsense!
雖然還不太明白
But I guess I have no choice!
但我也只能照做了，不是嗎？
So let's just get this game over with
既然如此，那就趕緊把遊戲玩完吧
and have some fun!
然後好好享受一番
Then the first round begins!
第一回合開始
This is
這裡是
the sports field?
運動場？
SHADOW STEP ROUND ONE
（映影頭踏，第一回合）
Now, fight with everything you've got!
現在，盡情戰鬥吧
That was a close one.
好險啊
He's fast. Who is this guy?
他動作很快，這傢伙是什麼人？
Now,
現在
it's my turn.
輪到我了
Teruasa!
照朝君
That tattoo…
那個刺青…
OROCHI, Search Takeru Hyodo.
大蛇，搜尋兵頭猛
There's no connection, so I can't get the data.
這裡沒有網路訊號 我沒辦法取得數據
Shit.
該死
Wait. Where are you going?
等等，你去哪裡？
He's here! He's a fighter who was banned for rigging matches.
找到了，他是格鬥手 因為搞黑箱而被禁賽
HYODO TAKERU BANNED FOR LIFE FOR CHEATING
（兵頭猛，因作弊而被終生禁賽）
I knew it.
正如我所料
I recognized his tattoo.
我認得他的刺青
A while back,
前一陣子
Hyodo disappeared from the public eye
他被發現搞黑箱
after he was caught rigging games to help pay off his gym's debts.
償還所屬訓練館的債務 然後就銷聲匿跡了
Now there's a rumor he's unbeatable in the underground fighting scene.
現在據說他在地下格鬥場上無人能敵
There's no way Teruasa can win against someone like that.
和這樣的人比賽會死的
I'm gonna get that key!
我要拿到那把鑰匙
The weak are so desperate.
以一個弱者來說，你還滿拚的嘛
Look at you thrashing around,
拚盡全力
struggling so hard just to find an opening.
垂死掙扎，就為了製造有利局面
Take this!
看招
there are two types of people in this world.
你知不知道世上有兩種人？
Those who win for themselves,
一種人為自己而贏
and those who lose everything to total strangers!
另一種人為毫不相干的人而輸掉一切
That's my life lesson to you.
這就是我送給你的人生教訓
Takeru Hyodo
兵頭猛
has stepped on a shadow.
在“映影頭踏”中
One point secured.
獲得一分
Time for round two.
現在進行第二回合
Here's your next arena!
這是下一個場地
SHADOW STEP ROUND 2
（映影頭踏，第二回合）
Teruasa!
照朝
How'd it go?
怎麼樣？
I lost the first round.
我第一回合輸了
Come on.
跟我來
A pro fighter?
職業格鬥手？
Yes. Seems he was banned from playing
對，他似乎被禁賽了
after he played illegal matches
因為他違法搞黑箱
to help the gym where he trained pay off its debt.
幫助所屬的訓練館償還債務
Right…
這樣啊？
You're in the lead by one point, huh?
你領先了一分？
You've got this.
厲害
You were there?
你剛才也在？
I'm your second.
我是你的下一個
I've got a great strategy.
我有一個絕妙的策略
Wanna hear it?
你想聽嗎？
You really wanna win, right?
你是真的想贏，對吧？
Anyway,
總之
why did you say that?
你為什麼要那樣說？
You said you'd take Hyodo's life.
你說要奪取兵頭的性命
I want the right to take Hyodo's life freely.
我要自由奪取兵頭猛性命的權利
No matter what situation we've got ourselves into,
不論我們陷入何種境地
no matter how bad that guy is,
不論那個傢伙有多惡劣
you don't have the right to take his life.
你都沒有權利奪取他的性命吧？
It's all meaningless if I don't win.
如果我贏不了，那就沒有意義了
What are you saying?
你說什麼？
Ui, leave it.
初君，別這樣
If we don't work together to win the game,
如果我們不團結起來贏這場遊戲
all three of us will be destroyed by the devil.
我們三個都會被惡魔除掉
Hey, look.
你們看
Our shadows are stretching towards the hallway.
我們的影子在朝走廊延伸
So it must be more advantageous
所以如果要在大樓裡踩影子
to be on the hallway side of the building.
站在走廊那邊會更有利
Don't ya think that's a little naive?
這個想法太天真了，悠季
Did you call me, "ya"?
你叫我“悠季”？
There's nowhere to hide in the hallway.
在走廊裡沒有藏身的地方
So it'll be a game of stamina.
所以這會是一場耐力賽
Which isn't exactly Teruasa's strong point.
這完全不是照朝君的強項
Isn't that a little rude?
你說得也太直接了
I must be making progress!
我這是在進化
Magic.
魔術
The game we used to play in the hallway upstairs.
我們以前常常在樓上的走廊玩的遊戲
That's it.
沒錯
-Ready? -Yep.
-好了嗎？ -好了
Three, two, one.
三、二、一
-Incredible. -Amazing.
-好神奇 -太厲害了
Three, two, one.
三、二、一
Thank you.
謝謝
What? How did you do that?
你們是怎麼做到的？
Well－
其實…
Here you are!
你們在這裡啊
Run!
快跑
Yuki, hide somewhere.
悠季，快躲起來
Come out wherever you are!
快出來，織田
Or I'm gonna break this guy's neck!
否則我擰斷這傢伙的脖子
Don't be a coward!
你這是懦弱之舉，兵頭
Teruasa, I can see your shadow. Go!
照朝，我能看到你的影子，快跑
Got you!
踩中你了
I win.
我贏了
A dummy?
是假人？
Teruasa Oda has stepped on a shadow.
織田照朝踩中了影子
One point secured!
得一分
I used to hide there all the time to play tricks.
以前變魔術時，我總是一直藏在這裡
Three, two, one.
三、二、一
-Three, two, one. -Was that real?
-三、二、一 -是真的嗎？
Right, Ui?
對吧，初？
Now it's one point each.
現在兩人各得一分了
Whoever wins round three will be the final winner.
贏得第三回合的人將是最終的勝者
The final game should be even more entertaining.
最後一回合將會更加有意思
SHADOW STEP ROUND 3
（映影頭踏，第三回合）
I can't see my shadow.
我看不到自己的影子
The gymnasium.
這裡是體育館
The haunted house from the school festival.
也是校慶裡的鬼屋
Where is it? Where's your shadow?
在哪裡？你的影子在哪裡？
Hey, Hyodo.
兵頭
You're a pro fighter, aren't you?
你是職業格鬥手吧？
So what!
那又怎麼樣？
What you really want
你真正想要的
isn't money or power.
不是金錢或權力
You want to be in the spotlight again.
你想重新回到聚光燈下
If that's so, then you don't need the key.
如果是那樣，你根本不需要惡魔鑰匙
You can achieve it by effort alone.
你光憑努力也做得到
Don't give into desire!
不要屈服於欲望
Then you don't need the key either?
那你也不需要惡魔鑰匙囉？
But you want it.
但你想得到它
You hide behind a mask of innocence,
裝作一副天真無辜的樣子
but it's you who has already given into desire!
實際上屈服於欲望的人就是你
Perhaps the need for revenge
也許復仇的決心
is also a form of desire.
也是一種欲望吧
But
但是
if I'm going to find who killed my father,
為了找到殺害我父親的凶手
I'll do anything for the keys!
我無論如何都要得到惡魔鑰匙
Shit.
該死
Hey, I was looking for you.
我們一直在找你
Hyodo is nearby.
兵頭就在附近
What are you planning to do with that?
你拿這些東西打算做什麼？
I'm going to trap him. You two hide here.
我要給兵頭設陷阱，你們躲在這裡
Yuki,
悠季
I need OROCHI to do some calculations.
我需要大蛇幫我計算
OROCHI isn't operating fully. What do you need to calculate?
現在大蛇無法完全運行 你需要計算什麼？
Timing.
時機
Oda!
織田
Show yourself!
快出來
Hyodo's extremely agile,
兵頭的行動極其敏捷
so I need to stop his movements at just the right time.
所以我需要在合適的時間 讓他無法靈活行動
I'll use the devil power "Limited Perfect"
到時我會使用“有限完美” 這個惡魔之力
to stop the curtain handle from moving.
使布簾橫杆無法移動
LIMITED PERFECT
（有限完美，凍結一分鐘）
Then, I'll cut the rope supporting the handle.
接著我會剪斷支撐橫杆的繩索
Now.
就是現在
Hyodo.
兵頭
Oda!
織田
Ten,
十
nine,
九
eight, seven…
八、七…
-Give it up. -Six…
-放棄吧 -六…
Five,
五
four,
四
three, two…
三、二…
Just as planned.
跟計畫一模一樣
Why didn't the curtain fall?
布簾為什麼沒落下來？
The key to this game
這場遊戲的關鍵
is simply a difference in ability.
是實力的差距
Things don't always go to plan.
事情也有不按照計畫進行的時候
This is your graveyard.
這是你的墳墓
Teruasa!
照朝
Ui!
初
Don't be an idiot!
別犯傻
The idiot is the one not stepping on his shadow!
現在不踩他影子的人才犯傻
Get it, Teruasa!
快踩啊，照朝
That's it!
遊戲結束
Teruasa Oda
織田照朝
takes the lead with two points.
首先獲得兩分
Therefore, victory goes to
因此勝者就是
Teruasa Oda.
織田照朝
Wait!
慢著
In accordance with the rules,
依照遊戲規則
the devil's key in Takeru Hyodo's possession
兵頭猛所擁有的惡魔鑰匙
goes to Teruasa Oda.
將歸織田照朝所有
After Takeru Hyodo has told Teruasa Oda
在兵頭猛向織田照朝講述
all that he knows about the devil's keys,
他對惡魔鑰匙所掌握的所有資訊後
he will lose his life.
他將失去性命
I'm going to die.
我要死了
After I go,
在我消失以後
just like Maruko－
和丸子一樣…
Wait.
等等
Gado,
卡多
now I know what happened last time.
現在我知道上一次是怎麼回事了
What?
什麼？
Last time,
上一次
I made my bet carefully so that Maruko wouldn't die.
我為了不讓丸子死 而特意謹慎地下賭注
I demand the right to take Maruko's life at any moment.
我要隨時都可以奪走丸子性命的權利
After the game,
在遊戲結束後
I said I'd take Maruko's life in 200 years,
為了救丸子，我說了
to save him from death.
要在兩百年以後再取他的性命
But he disappeared anyway.
但丸子還是消失了
When the first demands were made,
當第一個要求被提出來後
Maruko lost his temper, and you accepted his words.
丸子一氣之下說了一句話 隨後你接受了他說的話
If I lose,
如果我輸了
you can kill me on the spot.
你可以當場殺了我
My demand was overwritten.
那句話取代了我的要求
That's why he disappeared?
所以他就是這樣消失的？
This time, I made sure to overwrite Hyodo's words.
這一次，我刻意等到 兵頭提出要求之後才說出口
If I lose, you can take my life!
如果我輸了，你可以要了我的命
How entertaining. It is done－
真有意思，我同意
Don't you dare!
開什麼玩笑？
Gado.
卡多
I want the right to take Hyodo's life freely.
我要自由奪取兵頭猛性命的權利
You cannot kill Hyodo against my will.
你不能違背我的意願殺死兵頭
I have the right to take his life.
我擁有奪取他性命的權利
I will be the one to decide when to do so.
何時要他的命由我來決定
Fine.
好吧
Then the Shadow Step game is over!
那麼“映影頭踏”這個遊戲結束了
You saved my life.
你救了我的命
Was that your plan all along?
你從一開始就是這樣計畫的？
Yes.
對
Like I said,
我說過
it's all meaningless if I don't win.
如果我贏不了，那就沒有意義了
But in the end,
但是到頭來
I got you two mixed up in it.
我還是把你們捲進來了
I'm sorry.
抱歉
At a time like this,
這種時候
don't you mean "thank you"?
你不是應該說“謝謝”嗎？
We're your friends.
我們是你的朋友
Thank you.
謝謝
Take it.
拿去
Hyodo, where did you get this key?
兵頭，你是從哪裡得到這把鑰匙的？
It just suddenly fell in front of me.
幾天前，它突然從天而降
The same thing that happened to Maruko.
和丸子說的一樣
Then who told you about me?
那麼是誰跟你提起我的事？
Senya Uesugi.
上杉潛夜
Senya Uesugi?
上杉潛夜？
That's all I know about the keys.
這就是我對惡魔鑰匙所瞭解的一切
TO US WHEN WE ARE 20 JUNE 24TH, 2012
（致20歲的我們）
So, 13 years later, it's time to watch the video!
那麼，過了13年 是時候看這段影片了
Here goes!
開始囉
Very good.
期待已久
First up, Teruasa.
照朝君先來
Three, two, one, go!
三、二、一，開始
TO US WHEN WE ARE 20 TERUASA ODA
（致20歲的我們，織田照朝）
Hi, 20-year-old me. Are you watching?
嗨，20歲的我，你在看影片嗎？
Have you got a driver's license?
你拿到駕照了嗎？
Did you get a girlfriend?
你交女朋友了嗎？
Wow, you're acting all grown up.
你像個成年人一樣
Second-year Teruasa didn't have a girlfriend.
初二的照朝沒有女朋友
Teruasa, what's your dream for the future?
照朝君，你未來的夢想是什麼？
I want to go to Canada and see the northern lights.
我要去加拿大看北極光
Aren't you going to take over Oda Group?
你不是要接管織田集團嗎？
That's kinda a long way off.
那是更久以後的事了
But you do wanna take over eventually?
那你有接管的打算嗎？
Ui's next.
下一個是初君
Three, two, one, go!
三、二、一，開始
TO US WHEN WE ARE 20 UI SAITO
（致20歲的我們，齊藤初）
TO ME WHEN I AM 20
我想開一家屬於自己的
I want to start my own IT company.
IT公司
-It came true. -Shush.
夢想成真了
I'm kinda interested in that too.
我對這個也很感興趣
Really? You too, Yuki?
是嗎？悠季也感興趣？
That's a bit fishy.
真可疑啊
Is Yuki the reason you're interested in IT?
你不是因為悠季才對IT感興趣的吧？
No! Get off camera!
才不是，你走開啦
But that's so iffy, don't ya think?
但這真的很可疑，你不覺得嗎？
No! Stop it!
才沒有，別亂說
Looks like this isn't the first time you two have fallen out.
看來你們從以前開始就喜歡吵來吵去
Three, two, one, go!
三、二、一，開始
TO US WHEN WE ARE 20 YUKI MANABE
（致20歲的我們，真鍋悠季）
Last up, me.
最後是我
When I'm 20…
等到我20歲的時候…
Gonna be an AI developer?
你要當人工智能開發者嗎？
Teruasa, get out the way.
照朝，你別入鏡
When I'm 20, I hope I'm still friends with you two.
希望到我20歲的時候 我還能跟你們兩個做朋友
That's all!
就這樣
THE END
（結束）
What a cute friendship.
好感人的友情
It nearly made me cry.
我都感動到快哭了
Who are you?
你是誰？
Senya Uesugi?
上杉潛夜？
Call me Senya.
叫我潛夜就行了
And you are?
你是？
That's right.
對了
Can I call you Terurin?
我能叫你小照照嗎？
How do you know who I am? Who are you?
你是怎麼知道我是誰？你是什麼人？
Who?
什麼人？
Let's see…
我想想…
Does this answer your question?
這樣能回答你的問題嗎？
Are you an accomplice of my father's killer?
你是我殺父仇人的同夥？
Do you mean
你是指
Hoshin?
崩心？
You're kidding?
不會吧？
You don't know?
你不知道？
You don't know about his organization?
你不知道他的組織？
What do you mean, "organization"?
你說的“組織”是什麼意思？
I'll tell you once the game is over.
等遊戲結束了，我再告訴你
Oh, yes.
對
I forgot you've got all this baggage with you.
我忘了你還拖著這些包袱呢
Who are you calling baggage?
你說誰是包袱？
Why don't you and I discuss this elsewhere?
我和你到別處商量此事吧
Teruasa.
照朝
I'm going to give you
我會讓你品嚐
the greatest thrill of your life.
人生中最刺激的體驗
NEXT EPISODE
（下集預告）
Play the game with me.
跟我玩遊戲
TERUASA VS A GENIUS GAMBLER
（照朝對戰天才賭客）
You're the best.
你最棒了
He's not just after the keys.
他不僅僅想要獲得鑰匙
Guess the card symbol.
（五印一當）
This is "Five One."
這就叫“五印一當”
A master of his craft,
他是技藝高超的大師
he's got me in the palm of his hand.
把我玩弄在股掌之中